

ALEKSEI BORODIN

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER JAVA, KOTLIN, GROOVY

+79514877380 | +998947043877

swizbizy@gmail.com ▼ telegram.me/swizbiz

in linkedin.com/in/aleksei-borodin

github.com/swizbiz

dzone.com/users/4755732/swizbiz.html

EXPERIENCE

Senior Java Software Engineer **HUAWEI**

Mar 2022 - Present

Project: Artipie - binary artifact management tools, similar to Artifactory.

- Implemented a new repository adapter for Erlang\Elixir artifacts. Artiple is the first and only binary manager tool supporting Elixir\Erlang packages.
- Researched the QUIC protocol to support HTTP/3 in the Huawei Cloud.
- Implemented and contributed to an open-source GitHub Action to automatically update the year in the license files in the project.
- Wrote articles about Artipie to promote it in the developer community. Technologies: Java 17, Vert.X, RxJava, Reactive Streams, Docker, Maven, GitHub Actions, JUnit, Testcontainers, Prometheus, Grafana.

Java Software Engineer

Oct 2019 - Mar 2022

SBERBANK

Project: SberFriend - internal portal for all employees in the Sberbank ecosystem to get all the help they need (get IT support, find a colleague's contact, schedule a vacay). Developed backend for a low-code platform for the creation of micro-application (similar to apps in WeChat) for SberFriend.

- Split monolith running on IBM WebSphere into microservices on Spring Boot, that run in OpenShift, which reduced time to market by 7 times.
- Migrated the database from Oracle to PostgreSQL, which allowed removing the vendor lock and reducing license costs by \$1,000,000 a year.
- Automated the process of passing the task through the life cycle reduce manual processing tasks from 700 to 30 tasks per day.
- Developed a plugin for Intellij Idea for internal micro-applications, which helps to create, test, build a package of micro-applications and deploy it directly from Idea.

Technologies: Java 7 -> 11, Groovy, Kotlin, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Maven, Gradle, Jenkins, IBM WebSphere -> Openshift, JUnit, Mockito, Docker, H2, Oracle -> PostgreSQL, Liquibase, SonarQube, Prometheus, Grafana, Dynatrace, BitBucket, Swagger, OpenAPI, Eclipse MAT, VisualVM.

Java Developer

May 2019 - Sep 2019

TOPJAVA

 Developed an enterprise application with authorization and role-based access rights, stored in a database, and deploy to a Heroku cloud platform. <u>Technologies</u>: Java 8, Spring(Core, MVC, Security, Data), JDBC, JPA, Hibernate, PostgreSQL, HSQLDB, H2, Maven, Heroku, RESTful API, JUnit, Mockito, JavaScript, Bootstrap, ¡Query.

1C Developer **RARUS**

Jan 2018 - Sep 2019

• Developed and optimized the company's business processes to optimize the coordination of revenue contracts - an increase in profits of 17%. Technologies: 1C, PostgreSQL, SQL, SQLite, Linux, Bash.

SUMMARY

I'm a passionate software engineer with 5+ years of experience in IT and 4 years in Java. I have extensive hands-on experience in Java, Kotlin, Groovy languages, Microservices, Spring framework, and Hibernate. I'm always open to new technologies and opportunities to improve my skills. I also lead an active and diverse lifestyle.

And I have an awesome mustache;)

EDUCATION

Master's Degree in Computer Science Information security of automated systems Chelyabinsk State University - 2011-2016

CERTIFICATES

2019, Base course of Java - Certificate of completion with honors, Computer Science Center

2019, Java Developer Course, JavaRush

LANGUAGES

English - B2 Russian - Native

SKILLS

- · Base: Java 17, Groovy, Kotlin, OOP, SOLID.
- Frameworks: Spring (Boot, Data, Security, MVC, Cloud), Vert.X, RxJava, Hibernate.
- · DevOps: Docker, Kubernetes, Openshift, Git, Jenkins, SonarQube, GitHub Actions.
- Build tools: Maven, Gradle, Jib.
- Test: JUnit, Testcontainers, Mockito, TDD.
- Databases: Oracle, PostgreSQL, Liquibase.
- Monitoring: Prometheus, Dynatrace, Grafana, Java Flight Record(JFR).
- Profiling: Eclipse MAT, JProfiler, VisualVM.
- Other: BitBucket, Swagger, OpenAPI, Jira, Confluence, Scrum, Agile, Kanban.